<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tidyverse on Pete Talbert</title>
    <link>/tags/tidyverse/</link>
    <description>Recent content in tidyverse on Pete Talbert</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/tidyverse/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>For loops for quick summaries in R</title>
      <link>/post/for-loops-for-quick-summaries-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/for-loops-for-quick-summaries-in-r/</guid>
      <description>Because I often work with categorical data, I find myself making lots of quick, sorted counts of variables in a dataset. I find that this is a really common technique to get to know a dataset you’re working with; I’ve also noticed David Robinson do it often in his screencasts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Window Functions in SQL vs. R</title>
      <link>/post/window-functions-in-sql-vs-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/window-functions-in-sql-vs-r/</guid>
      <description>Both MS SQL Server and R’s dplyr package offer window functions for different operations on a dataset. What are window functions? Window functions operate on a set of rows or “window” and return a value for each row, whether that’s something like a row number or percentile rank, or an aggregate result from a min, max, average, or sum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plotting factors with forcats</title>
      <link>/post/ggplot2-tips-for-categories/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/ggplot2-tips-for-categories/</guid>
      <description>Often, I find myself with a lot of categorical variables that I want to plot, where I’m really only interested in the most common ones that bubble to the surface.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pivoting Data in SQL vs. R</title>
      <link>/post/pivoting-data-in-sql-vs-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/pivoting-data-in-sql-vs-r/</guid>
      <description>Often with education data, I need to pivot data to go from long format to wide. For instance, I often have test scores for different test subjects of a single assessment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ggplot2 geom_bar Labeling</title>
      <link>/post/ggplot2-geom-bar-labeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/ggplot2-geom-bar-labeling/</guid>
      <description>In educational data analysis, I am constantly looking at counts and proportions. I’ve found the easiest way to display these results with categorical variables like demographics is to use stacked bar charts and especially 100% stacked charts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>